# **ARPIT DWIVEDI**

Portfolio link: <a href="http://arpit-dwivedi.me/">http://arpit-dwivedi.me/</a>

## +91 9532294061

≥ 8arpitdwivedi798@gmail.com

https://github.com/arpit-dwivedi
in www.linkedin.com/in/dwivedi-arpit/

🎙 <u>datascienceplus.com/author/arpit-dwivedi/</u>

#### SUMMARY

Digital Specialist Engineer trained on .NET core full stack Web Development. I also have knowledge and certifications in Machine Learning and Computer vision. I'm no stranger to hard work and my strength is I am flexible with work hours and time bound. I am always curious to learn something new.

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

- DOB 12th January, 1998
- Father's Name- Mr. C.B Dwivedi
- Permanent Address- E-12/1,
   Sarvodaya Nagar, Lko 226016

#### **EDUCATION**

- BACHELORS OF TECHNOLOGY (Computer Science Engineering)
   GLA University, Mathura, U.P. 2016-2020
- SECONDARY SCHOOL
   Rani Laxmi Bai Memorial School,
   Lucknow, U.P. -2015
- HIGH SCHOOL
   Rani Laxmi Bai Memorial School,
   Lucknow ,U.P.-2013

#### **CORE SKILLS**

- C#
- Microsoft SQL
- .NET Full Stack Web Development.
- Angular
- Python
- Machine Learning
- Computer Vision
- Docker basics
- Flask

#### OTHER SKILLS

- Leadership
- Duty Bound
- Ability to Work Under Pressure.
- Writing Skills
- Fast Learner
- Team Player

#### **EXPERIENCE**

• Digital Specialist Engineer - Infosys

Trained on: C#, SQL Server, Entity Framework Core, ASP.NET Core Web API, Angular 9.

### OTHER RESPONSIBILITIES / TRAININGS

• **<u>DevIncept</u>** - Founded Open-source community

• StudentCode-in - Contributed to DiversitAI

• **IOTIOT.in** - AI Core Tech Skilling & Internship

• Udacity -

Machine learning with Tensorflow Computer Vision

achine learning with Tensorflow Nanodegree

Nanodegree

(Aug 2020 - Present)

(June 2020 - Aug 2020)

(April 2020 - Aug 2020)

(January 2021 to Present)

• Internshala - Data Science Training

(June, 2019 to July 2019)

#### **PROJECTS**

- **Image segmentation API:** Built a multi client web application with FastAPI, which takes an image and gives segmentation result in JSON format.
- **Personal Portfolio** Created a portfolio website using Bootstrap Studio and hosted it on Github pages.
- **DevIncept Website** Built a website for DevIncept community.
- Live Sketch App Created a live sketching app. It uses a live video from webcam and extracts the edges to create a sketch drawing effect. Further integrated it with Flask and deployed it on Heroku.
- **Object Detection** Detect a Specific Object Using both SIFT or ORB.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- 37k + views on Articles on <u>Datascience+</u> community.
- Paper published in International Journal of Advanced Science and Technology.
- Ranking in top 1% <u>Kaggle Notebook Expert</u>.
- Featured on AI Wall of Fame for being top performer in IOTIOT.in.
- Cleared **Hackwithinfy** and got selected for **SES** role in Infosys.
- Certification in Machine Learning with Python by IBM on Coursera.
- Two certifications in **Data Science by IBM** on Coursera.
- Four certifications in Python by University of Michigan on Coursera.
- Certification in Introduction to Deep Learning by National Research University Higher School of Economics on Coursera.

#### EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Participated in COMET'17 organized by Mechanical Engineering Society, IIT BHU(Varanasi).
- Participated in Sherlocked Workshop in E-WEEK at GLA university.
- Participated in Loopholes Workshop in E-WEEK at GLA university.

Date: Signature